… Her name is Mataji Nirmala Devi.
...Kendisinin ismi,  Mataji Nirmala Devi.
She trained as a doctor in India
Hindistan`da bir doktor olarak eğitim görmüş
and She is now married to a senior diplomat at the United Nations.
ve Birleşmiş Milletlerde üst düzey bir diplomat ile evli.
She lives in London,
Londra`da yaşıyor
but this week She’s holding a series of public meetings
ama bu hafta öğretilerini halka duyurmak için,
to publicize Her teachings.
bir seri halk toplantısı yapıyor.
She believes that we all have a form of spiritual energy
Kendisi, omurganın altında bulunan, uyandırılabilen
called Kundalini at the base of our spines,
ve akması için bedene gönderilen Kundalini adı verilen spiritüel
which can be awakened and sent flowing through the body.
bir enerji formunun hepimizde bulunduğuna inanıyor.
So I took my shoes off
Bu yüzden ayakkabılarımı kaptım
and went to meet Her in Northampton this morning.
ve bu sabah Northampton`a Onunla buluşmaya gittim.
SHRI MATAJI: You are a person who is more active
SHRI MATAJİ: Siz daha aktif ve çok fazla düşünmeye,
and tries to think too much, work too much…
çok fazla çalışmaya çalışan bir kişisiniz.
REPORTER: I think too much?
MUHABİR: Ben çok fazla mı düşünüyorum?
Nobody ever said that to me before. Right,...
Hiç kimse bunu daha önce bana söylemedi. Doğru…
SHRI MATAJI: And you work too much physically,
SHRI MATAJİ: Ve siz fiziksel olarak çok fazla çalışıyorsunuz,
you run about and you are more working outside.
koşturuyorsunuz ve daha çok dışarıda çalışıyorsunuz.
And left side is the emotional side,
Ve sol taraf, duygusal taraftır,
so left side — for emotional life.
yani sol taraf duygusal hayat içindir.
Well, that’s what is the imbalance in you is.
Güzel, işte sizdeki dengesizlik bu.
Now for this we have to first give you a balance,
Şimdi bunun için önce size bir denge vermemiz gerek,
all right? What I'll do is to awaken your frozen side
tamam mı?  Yapacağım şey, donmuş olan tarafı uyandırmak
and bring it down so the grace
ve onu aşağıya indirmek, bu sayede
comes over here to satisfy this side.
bu tarafı tatmin etmek için lütuf buraya gelir.
So it is to be awakened, you see, the emotional side is awakened.
Yani bu uyandırılacak, bakın, duygusal tarafı uyandı.
And this side is given a sort of a soothing effect
Ve bu taraf, Her Yeri Saran güç ile sizin sağ tarafınızdan
with the all-pervading Power from your right.
gelen bir tür rahatlatıcı efekt verdi.
So this is, this is how it moves, right? This is the way.
Yani  sağ hareketi bu şekildedir. Yolu bu.
REPORTER: But is this energy and this desire any more
MUHABİR: Ama bu enerji ve bu arzu,
than the desire that everyone has to make the best of himself,
herkesin kendisi için en iyisini yapmak, mutlu olmak,
to be happy, to be content?
memnun olmak için duyduğu arzudan  daha mı fazladır?
SHRI MATAJI: You cannot be contented with material things.
SHRI MATAJİ: Maddi şeylerle memnun olamazsınız. Olamazsınız.
You cannot be. That’s the basic principle of economics.
Bu ekonominin temel prensibidir.
REPORTER: So can I put a contradiction to You,
MUHABİR: Öyleyse ben size bir itirazda bulunabilir miyim,
that in the past when all the gurus
geçmişte bütün bu gurular
have all seemed to be surrounded by a great deal
hepsi çok zengin ziynetlerle, büyük miktarda zenginlik
of very affluent trappings, great deal of wealth and money.
ve para ile donanmış görülüyorlardı.
That seemed to be a great contradiciton of
Bu onların söylediklerine  büyük bir tezatmış gibi göründü.
SHRI MATAJI: I’m happy you see that, but how many see that?
Bunu gördüğünüz için mutluyum, ama kaç tanesi bunu gördü?
Is something one should understand, that it is not a business,
Kişinin anlaması gereken bir şey bu. Bu bir iş değildir,
you cannot make money out of …
bundan dolayı para kazanamazsınız.
REP: But they’re making a very successful business out of it.
MUHABİR: Ama onlar bunu kullanarak çok başarılı bir iş yapıyorlar.
You must come to right conclusions,
Sizler doğru yargılara ulaşmalısınız,
that if something has to happen to you,
eğer size bir şey olması gerekiyorsa,
it will be in your awareness.
bu sizin farkındalığınız içinde olacaktır.
You have to manifest your powers, and then only you will realize
Güçlerinizi göstermelisiniz ve kendi evriminiz için
that you cannot pay money for your evolution.
para ödeyemeyeceğinizi ancak o zaman anlayacaksınız.
REPORTER: Now we’ve got perhaps three million people
MUHABİR: Şimdi şu anda bizi izleyen
watching us at the moment.
belki de üç milyon kişi var.
Should they be able to feel anything or to gain anything
Sadece sizi televizyonda izledikleri için her hangi bir şey hissediyor
from watching You just on the television?
veya bir şeyler kazanıyor olmalılar mı?
SHRI MATAJI: Yes, some of them may.
Evet, bazıları bunu yapabilirler.
If they are just there, if they put their hands towards Me
Eğer orada iseler, eğer ellerini şimdi
just now even like this,
Bana doğru böyle tutarlarsa,
they might feel the cool breeze in their hands.
ellerinde serin esintiyi hissediyor olabilirler.
And then they might feel on their heads coming out the cool breeze.
Ve belki de onlar başlarının üstünden serin esintinin geldiğini hissedebilirler.
I mean, it has happened in so many places.
Demek istiyorum ki, bu bir çok yerde oldu.